Doctor Who 1963 05x05 (whopix fan edit)
The Web of Fear
神秘博士老版 第五季第五集 恐惧之网 （粉丝剪辑版）
（注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频，而是针对 Whopix 粉丝剪辑版本 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-1e1 ）
- Mr Silverstein?   - Yes. Who are you?
- Silverstein 先生吗?  - 是, 你是谁?
Anne Travers. Is my father here?
Anne Travers．我父亲在这里吗?
Yes, he's here. Come and see him and take him away.
是的, 他在这儿．来看一下, 把他带走吧
He's a fool. An old fool!
他糊涂了, 老糊涂了
Father?
父亲？
Father...
父亲...
Anne...
- What are you doing here?
- Looking for you.
- 你在这里做什么？   - 找你啊
You were supposed to be meeting me.
你原本应该去接我
- Was I?   - At the airport.
- 是吗？    - 在机场
Father, what is the matter? You send me a cable saying you're in grave trouble.
父亲，是怎么回事？你给我发了电报，说你遇到大麻烦了
- And I fly half the way round the world...
- Trouble? Yes.
- 我飞了大半个地球...   - 麻烦? 是的
A great deal of trouble. It's that thing.
很大的麻烦．是那个东西
- The Yeti?   - Mm.
- 雪怪？      - 嗯
You're a stupid old fool, Julius Silverstein!
你是个愚蠢的糊涂蛋, Julius Silverstein！
ME the fool? You would like me to be the fool and give you back my Yeti, huh?
我是糊涂蛋？你就期望我是糊涂蛋, 好把雪怪还给你, 哈？
You must, man. Don't you understand? It's dangerous.
你必须, 伙计．你不明白吗？它太危险了
For 30 years this stands here in my museum, and now he tells me it is dangerous!
在我的博物馆放了３０年, 现在你跟我说它很危险！
- I wish I'd never brought it back from Tibet.
- Father, what has happened?
- 我期望我没有把它从西藏带回来   - 父亲, 发生了什么？
The silly old goat won't listen to me. I've told him, warned him.
这头老笨山羊不听我的．我告诉他了, 警告他了
- Damn it, he knows it's a robot!
- But, Father, the Yeti isn't dangerous.
- 蛋, 他知道它是个机器人   - 但是, 父亲, 雪怪并不危险
It can't work unless it has a control unit.
没有那个控制器它是不会启动的
But I've done it, Anne!
但我搞定了, Anne！
I HAVE reactivated the control unit.
我已经重新激活了控制器
But, Father, this is wonderful news.
啊, 父亲, 这是非常好的消息啊
Is it? Yes, I suppose it would be, except for one thing.
是吗？是, 我也觉得是, 除了一件事
What?
什么？
The sphere - it's gone!
那个球  - 不见了！
It's disappeared! You must let me have the Yeti back, Julius.
它消失了！你必须得让我把雪怪要回来, Julius
Make him understand, Anne!
你跟他说明白吧, Anne!
I understand.
我很明白
I buy the Yeti off you 30 years ago.
我30年前从你手里买走了雪怪
Now, it is valuable.
现在, 它值钱了
You try to scare me, take your Yeti back.
你就试图吓唬我, 好把你的雪怪要回去
Why? Money! You want to rob me!
为什么？钱！你想打劫我！
I'll buy the thing back if that's what you want!
我可以把它买回来, 如果你想要的是这个
No, no. It's priceless.
不, 不, 它是无价的
The only one in the world, and it is mine.
全世界独一无二的, 就我才有
- You fool!  - Thief!
- 你糊涂！    - 小偷！
- I'm not a thief.   - Swindler!
- 我不是小偷      - 骗子！
Stubborn old goat!
顽固的老山羊！
- Father!   - Take him away - out of my house!
- 父亲！   - 把他带走, 离开我的房子！
Father, perhaps you've made a mistake.
父亲，也许是你搞错了
You've put the sphere away somewhere in your laboratory and forgotten it.
你把那个球放在实验室里某个地方, 然后忘了
- You've done it before.
- No. I've looked everywhere.
- 你以前也干过这事   - 不, 我都找遍了
Let's go home and look again, shall we? You know what you're like.
我们回家去, 再找找, 行吗？你知道你是怎样的
Yes, but suppose...
好, 不过要是...
Let's go and have a quiet dinner, and you can tell me all about it.
走吧, 一起安静地用个晚餐, 你跟我详细说说
Then we'll go home and look for the sphere.
然后我们回家, 找那个球
Well, all right... But I warned you, Julius! I warned you!
好, 行吧...但我警告过你了, Julius! 我警告过你了
Get out! Take him away!
出去！把他带走！
Nobody destroys Julius Silverstein's collection! Nobody!
没谁能破坏 Julius Silverstein 的收藏品！没谁！
- Come on, Father.
- The Yeti's mine!
- 得啦, 父亲   - 雪怪是我的！
You can't scare me with your mad stories.
你别想用你的疯狂故事吓住我
Out! Out!
出去！出去！
Travers...
It is you? I am not frightened by your stupid tricks!
是你吗？我不会被你的愚蠢伎俩吓倒的
Travers! I know it's you.
Travers! 我知道是你
I'm not a fool!
我可不糊涂！
Agh!
啊！
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Web of Fear
Doctor Who 1963 05x05 (whopix fan edit)
神秘博士老版 第五季第五集 恐惧之网 （粉丝剪辑版）
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
（注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频，而是针对 Whopix 粉丝剪辑版本 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-1e1 ）
Some sort of grille.
某种栅栏
Don't say you've landed us in a prison!
可别说你降落到了一座监狱里！
It could be the dungeons of a castle.
可能是一座城堡的地牢
It's so dark.
好黑呀
Ah, steps.
啊, 台阶
Come along. Be careful.
过来, 小心点
Yes...
好...
It seems to be a large room.
看起来是个很大的房间
Tiled walls.
瓷砖墙
Curved ceiling.
拱形天花板
Come on.
快来
The floor seems to end here.
地面好像到这里就没有了
There's a sort of trench. Look.
这里有某种壕沟, 你看
- Hey, Doctor. Come and look at this.
- What have you found, Victoria?
- 嘿, 博士, 来看看这个   - 你发现了什么, Victoria？
See for yourself.
你自己看看
"Covent... Garden... "
"科文特...花园..."
（注：伦敦西部一街区名称, 特色是皇家歌剧院和诸多的小商店）
Yes, of course! It's an underground station. We're standing on the platform.
是了, 当然！这是一个地下车站, 我们站在月台上
- Underground station?   - Underground trains.
- 地下车站？   - 地铁
- A little after your time, Victoria.
- Is it always as dark as this?
- 略晚于你的时代, Victoria  - 总是这么黑吗？
No, it's probably the middle of the night. Come on. Let's go up top.
不．只是现在很可能是午夜．快来, 我们到顶上去
- Professor Travers is here, sir.
- Why have I been brought here? Who are you?
- Travers 教授来了, 先生  - 为什么带我来这儿？你是谁？
- Knight.       - Never heard of you.
- 我叫 Knight   - 从没听说过
Captain Knight. OK, Corporal.
Knight 上校。好了, 下士
It's no good shouting at me.
朝我喊可没什么好处
- I didn't ask for you.   - Who did, then?
- 不是我叫你来的   - 那是谁？
- Your daughter.   - Anne? Just like her mother.
- 你女儿   - Anne? 真像她妈
Always interfering in things she knows nothing about!
总是在她啥也不懂的事情上插手
I understood that you'd sent for her to come back from merica to help you.
我还以为是你把她从美国叫回来帮你的
What do you want me for, anyway?
你要我做什么？
I don't. I consider this to be a military matter.
不是我要。我认为这是一个军事问题
Well, you haven't much success so far, haven you?
那你到目前也还没获得什么成功, 是吧？
Army? What the devil do they know about it?
军方？他们到底对这个知道些什么？
- The Doctor was wrong!
- It's not night-time. It's broad daylight.
- 博士搞错了！   - 现在不是晚上, 是光天白日
- Just let me get my breath... Those stairs!
- It looks like we're locked in.
- 且让我喘口气...这些台阶！   - 看来我们被锁在里面了
- That's strange.  - Doctor...
- 这很奇怪啊     - 博士...
- Yes?    - Listen.
- 什么？   - 听
I can't hear anything.
我什么也没听到
Oh... It IS quiet. I see what you mean.
噢...是太安静了．我明白你的意思了
The middle of London. There should be some noise.
伦敦市中心, 应该会有些噪音才对
Hey, Doctor. There's an old man over there. Let's ask him.
嘿，博士，那儿有个老人, 我们去问问他
Yes, go on.
对, 去吧
Excuse me...
打扰一下...
Who are you?
你是谁？
- Harold Chorley. London Television.
- Oh, What?
- Harold Chorley. 伦敦电视台   - 噢，什么？
Television? Never watch it. Are you an actor or something?
电视台？从来没看过．你是个演员什么的吗？
Journalist, actually.
新闻记者, 实际上
The government decided to only allow one correspondent down here. The press chose me.
政府决定允许派一个新闻记者下来, 台里选了我
Oh, yeah?
噢, 那又怎样？
Tell me, Professor, will you be in charge of the scientific  ection, or will your daughter?
告诉我，教授，是你负责这里的科学组吗？还是你女儿
Mind your own business!
管好你自己的事！
And how long do you think it will take you to come up with the answer?
你觉得你需要多久才能得到答案？
- One week? Three, perhaps?
- How the hell should I know?
- 一周？三周, 也许要？  - 我怎么可能知道？
- Is that working?
- Of course.
- 那东西好使吗？   - 当然
It's more than likely we may not be able to defeat this menace.
感觉更像是, 我们可能无法消除这场危机
London...perhaps the whole of England might be completely wiped out. There - did you get that?
伦敦...也许整个英格兰都可能被完全毁灭．喏 - 你明白了吗？
- What are you doing, Doctor?
- Just confirming something.
- 你在干什么，博士？  - 只是确认点事情
Yes, just as I thought. There haven't been any trains here for some time.
是的，正如我所料, 这里有段时间没跑地铁了
What's that over there?
那边是什么？
It's a power cable. I wonder what it's doing down here.
是一根电缆．我很好奇它在这里有什么用
In there quickly!
进去那儿, 快！
Soldiers? I wonder what they're doing down here.
士兵？奇怪, 他们在这下面干什么？
- Let's go and ask them.
- No. I think we'd better tread carefully.
- 我们去问问他们   - 不, 我觉得我们还是小心行事
Let's go and find out what's going on first.
我们去看看是在干什么
What do you want us to do, Doctor?
你期望我们做什么, 博士？
You follow the soldiers, but keep out of sight.
你跟着那些士兵, 但别被看见了
I'm going to see where this cable goes to.
我要去看看这些线缆通向那里
Meet back here in a few minutes. Right?
过几分钟回来这里汇合。好吧？
- What's the matter?
- I thought I heard something.
- 怎么了？   - 我觉得我听到了点什么
- Getting a bit jumpy, aren't you, Weams?
- It's no wonder, is it, Staff?
- 有点神经质了吧, 是不, Weams?  - 那也不稀奇, 是吧, Staff?
- Shall we connect the new drum now, Staff?
- All right, Corporal.
- 我们现在要连上新桶了吧, Staff？  - 是, 下士
- Good thing we fixed these lights.
- Yeah. You said that again.
- 好的是我们把这些灯修好了  - 是，你说过了
- I can't hear anything.
- Are they still there?
- 我什么也听不见   - 他们还在那儿吗？
I think they must be moving. Come on.
我觉得他们肯定走了．快来
Agh!
啊！
I told you I heard something, didn't I?
我就说我听到了什么, 说过吧
Yeah. Come on!
是的。快来！
- I'm sorry!   - It was only a cobweb!
- 我很抱歉！   - 不过是蜘蛛网
- Do you think they heard?
- Hope not. Come on.
- 你觉得他们听到了吗？   - 但愿没有, 快来
Well, well, well, would you believe it? The Babes in the Wood!
好, 好, 好, 你能相信不？树林中的美女!
（备注：“树林中的美女”原为一童话故事名，后衍生为指在不知情的情况下进入危险境地的无辜者）
- You're quite sure there was nobody with you?
- How many more times?
- 你确定你们没有其他人？   - 还要说多少次？
That's all right, then.
那就没事了
- Clear to fire, Staff?
- Yes, they were on their own.
- 可以点火了吗, Staff?   - 是的, 就他们自己
Right.
好
What was all that about?
这都是怎么回事？
I suppose there's no harm in telling you. You two are very lucky.
我觉得告诉你也没有关系, 你们俩非常幸运
- We're going to blow up the tunnel.
- What?!
- 我们打算炸掉这个隧道   - 什么?!
- That's what the cable's for.
- The Doctor!
- 那些电缆是干这个的   - 博士！
It's all right. They were on their own. OK, let's not waste any more time. Off you go.
没问题了, 就他们自己．好, 我们不要再浪费时间, 走你
Agh!
啊
A doctor! Well, if he was anywhere near those explosives when they went up...
一位博士！如果炸药爆炸的时候他在那附近的话...
Yes sir. Don't you think I should go and have a look, sir?
是的长官。我是不是应该去看一下？
The youngsters said he was following the cable.
这两个年轻人说他们当时正沿着电缆在走
Yes, you'd better.
是，最好是
Sir!
是！
Oh, and Staff, take someone with you.
哦，Staff，带个人跟你一起
Sir!
是！
- Father?  - Hmm?
- 父亲？  - 嗯？
The soldiers have found two youngsters in the tunnels.
士兵们在隧道里发现了两个年轻人
They seem to know a great deal about the Yeti.
他们好像知道雪怪的不少事情
Oh?
哦？
They know they're robots!
他们知道雪怪是机器人！
What!
什么！
And they know about the control spheres, too.
而且他们也知道控制球的事情
But they can't have - I mean, the public were never told!
但是不可能啊，我是说，我们从来公开过啊！
I know.
我知道
Where are they?
他们在哪儿？
Hello, hello, Holborn?...
哈罗，哈罗，Holborn？...
This is HQ to Holborn. Can you hear me?... Not a sausage.
这里是总部呼叫 Holborn．你能听到吗？...一丁点儿也没有
There must be someone manning the phone.
肯定有谁在操纵电话线
OK, Lane, what gives?
好了, Lane, 什么情况
Well, it's just firing at the other end, sir.
另一端有人开火, 长官
- Firing?  - Yes, sir. Listen.
- 开火？ - 是的, 头儿．听
Oh, good grief, no!
噢, 可怜人, 不！
Hello, HQ to Holborn?
哈罗, 总部呼叫 Holborn
What happened, Lane?
怎么了, Lane
Well, it was difficult to hear, sir. I think the truck was late getting there...
嗯, 很难听清, 长官．我觉得卡车到那里晚了...
Then what?
那又怎样？
Well they must have got the ammo unloaded, sir, 'cos he says they were jumped when they were leaving.
他们肯定已经把弹药卸下来了, 头儿．因为他说他们正要离开的时候它们扑过来了
Take O'Brien and a couple of the others.
带上 O'Brien 等几个人
Sir! Come on, mate.
是！快来, 伙计们
Here, you're not going out there?
你不打算出去吧？
Yes, Mr Chorley. Want to come? Report some action first hand?
出去, Chorley 先生, 你想来？想获得第一手的报道？
Well, I don't think I'd better get in the way. I...
哦, 我觉得我还是不要碍事的好。我...
I think I'd better stay here, don't you?
我觉得待在这里更好, 是吧？
Yes. Yes, I think you better had.
是的, 是的, 我想你最好
Father?
父亲？
But it... it can't be...
但这...这不可能啊...
Why... that's... that's over... forty years ago!
为什么...那已经是...四十年前了！
What's going on here?
这里在干什么？
Oh Jamie, don't you recognise him? It's Professor Travers.
噢 Jamie, 你不认识他了？这是 Travers 教授
So it is! Professor Travers! Here, hasn't he got old!
还真是啊！Travers 教授！看, 他没怎么变老
Huh?
啊？
Oh, but we're very pleased to see you, Professor, very pleased.
噢, 我们都非常高兴见到你, 教授, 非常高兴
The time machine... it was all true then?
时间机器...这么说都是真的？
The TARDIS - I mean aye, of course it's true! Hey, do you know what's happened to the Doctor?
TARDIS - 我是说, 当然是真的！嘿, 你知道博士现在怎么样了？
Oh, is he safe?
哦, 他还安全吗？
Isn't he with you?
他没有跟你们在一起吗？
No, he's in the tunnels. Arnold's gone to look for him. Father, what is going on?
没, 他在隧道里．Arnold 去找他去了．父亲, 这是在干什么？
Oh dear, I do hope he's alright. Come on, Jamie, let's go and find out if he's got back yet.
亲爱的, 我真期望他没事．来, Jamie, 我们去看看他回来没有
Father!
父亲！
Eh? Oh, Victoria, try and explain to Anne, will you?
嗯？哦, Victoria, 你给 Anne 解释一下, 行吗？
Oh dear!
哦, 老天！
There hasn't been an explosion, Staff!
没有发生爆炸, Staff！
I can see that, lad... Here!
我看到了, 小伙子...过来！
No sign of that Doctor bloke.
没有见到这什么博士的影子
No... here, give me a hand with this.
没有...嘿, 给我搭把手
It's our detonator, alright. It's fired, too...
是我们的引爆器, 也已经引爆了...
'ere, hang on a minute. All the ammo, Staff. If it's fired, then why didn't...
等一下, 所有的弹药, Staff．如果已经引爆了, 为什么没有...
Yeah, why didn't this tunnel go up?... No damage at all...
是啊, 为什么这个隧道没有被炸掉？...完全没受损...
Yet something blew up here!
但这里的确爆炸了啊！
It's obvious, ain't it? It's been got at.
很显然, 对不？被人破坏了
Where's that Doctor? That's what I'd like to know.
那个博士在哪儿？这是我想知道的
Tibet? Tibet? You're joking.
西藏？西藏？你在开玩笑
That's where old Travers says they come from. He reckons they're Abominable Snowmen.
是 Travers 说它们就来自那儿. 他管他们叫做可恶的雪人
Well, he's off his chump, ain't he? How'd they get here in the first place?
他脑袋有问题吧, 是不？它们最开始是怎么到这里来的？
Come through the post, don't they?
邮递来的, 不是吗？
Nah, seriously. Outer space, that's where they come from. Well that's what I reckon, anyway.
严肃点．外太空, 那是它们来的地方．这是我的猜测
Oh do leave off! You've been reading too many kids' comics, you have!
噢, 得了吧！你看了太多小孩子的漫画书, 对不？
Alright then, Corp, where do they come from?
好吧．下士, 那他们是从那儿来的？
It's a foreign power, ain't it? Bacteriological warfare, that's what that stuff is in the tunnels.
应该是外国势力, 对不？细菌战争, 隧道里面的东西就是这个
What, that fungus stuff?
什么, 那些真菌？
Yeah. And them Yeti are some sort of new weapon. Well, a sort of robot army.
对, 那些雪怪就是某种新式武器, 一种机器人军队
What, you mean it ain't real then?
什么, 你是说他们不是真的动物？
Well of course they ain't, you nit!
当然不是真的, 你个废柴！
Otherwise we'd be able to knock 'em out with the small arms, wouldn't we?
否则我们就可以用小型武器搞定他们了, 对不？
Yeah - nothing hardly touches 'em, does it?
是啊 - 没什么能搞定它们了, 有吗？
Not unless you can cop 'em straight between the eyes. Then they've had it.
除非你直接对准它们两眼之间下手, 那它们就嗝屁了
Father?
父亲？
Hmm?
嗯？
Have you ever seen this TARDIS?
你见过 TARDIS 吗？
No, no, I can't say I have.
没, 没有, 我说不上见过
It all sounds a bit far-fetched to me.
在我听来感觉有点太不现实了
You know, I think the Doctor's at the back of all this.
你知道吗, 我觉得这一切都是博士在背后捣鬼
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Doesn't it strike you as odd that on the two occasions you've encountered the Yeti, you've also come across the Doctor?
你就从来没有觉得奇怪, 你两次遇到雪怪, 你都碰到了博士？
Well?
怎样？
Well, it's obvious - he controls them!
这, 很显然 - 他在控制他们！
Oh, but surely...
哦, 但当然...
What? Oh, tea. Thank you, my dear.
什么？哦, 茶．谢谢你, 亲爱的
Oh, aren't you having any?
哦, 你不喝点吗？
No, I think I'll go and lie down for a bit.
不了, 我想我要去躺一会儿
Good idea.
好主意
Do you think she heard?
你觉得她听到了吗？
No... in any case, what you say is nonsense, Anne.
不管怎么说, 你说的都是胡扯, Anne
I saw the Doctor defeat those robots and save Detsen Monastery.
我看见博士打败了那些机器人, 拯救了德赞寺
He wouldn't do that if he was in league with them, now would he?
如果他跟它们是一伙的, 他不会那么做的, 现在他会吗？
No, no I suppose not.
不, 我觉得不会
Here, Corp, look at this!
过来, 下士, 看看这个
What... oh crikey! That's what comes of talking about it!
什么...啊呀！真是说什么来什么
It's that fungus stuff, it's moving again!
是那些真菌, 它又在移动了！
Don't worry!
别担心
Can't help it - I feel... responsible somehow.
忍不住啊 - 不知怎的...我觉得我有责任
If only the Doctor would turn up. I'm sure he could help us.
如果博士能出现就好了, 我肯定他能帮上我们
'Scuse me, sir...
抱歉, 先生
Eh, what?
嗯, 什么？
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again. Euston Square's gone.
那些真菌, 又在移动了．尤斯顿广场没了
Come on, let's have a look!
快来, 我们来看看！
It's on the move again, Weams?
它又在移动了, Weams？
Yes, sir. Kings Cross has gone, and it's moving on to Farringdon.
是的, 先生, 国王十字车站也丢了．它现在往 Farringdon 站去了
It's never moved as fast as this before!
它以前从来没有移动得这么快过！
Hasn't moved at all the last three weeks, Miss.
前面三个星期都没移动过，小姐
What started it up again all of a sudden?
是什么东西突然间触发了它？
Can't say.
不好说
Strange, isn't it, that all this should happen on the very day that your mysterious Doctor friend turns up?
很奇怪啊，是不是，你的那位博士朋友出现的同一天，就发生了这么多事
He hasn't turned up.
他还没出现呢
Precisely. He could have sent those kids in here as spies.
的确．他可能是把那两个孩子派过来做间谍了
Rubbish! Would Jamie go away and leave Victoria, if he didn't intend coming back again?
胡说！你说 Jamie 不会再回来, 那他会留下 Victoria 一个人吗？
Excuse me, sir, but where is the young lady?
对不起, 先生, 但那个年轻女士在哪儿？
Oh, in the Common Room, I suppose.
哦, 在公共休息室, 我估计
No she's not, 'cos I went in there when I was looking for you!
不, 她没有．我刚才找你的时候到那里面去过了！
What? Well... where is she then?
什么？那...她在哪儿呢？
Jamie? Doctor?... Jamie? Doctor?
Jamie? 博士? ... Jamie? 博士?
Victoria!
Oh, Doctor, thank goodness I found you! Are you alright?
哦, 博士, 感谢上帝我找到你了！你没事吧
Look, sir, the fungus! It's moving again!
看, 头儿, 真菌！又在移动了！
Hope the Captain and Staff Arnold ain't anywhere near that little lot.
期望队长和 Staff Arnold 不在那个小东西的附近
Lane? Lane! Fall back, you'll never hold them!
Lane? Lane! 后撤, 你阻挡不了它们的！
Will nothing stop them?
没什么能挡住他们吗？
Come on, back!
快, 回来！
We couldn't hold 'em, sir. They're coming, two of 'em!
我们没法顶住他们, 头儿．他们来了, 有两个！
They got O'Brien and Cocksey, nothing stops them!
O'Brien 和 Cocksey 已经落入它们手上了, 没什么能挡住它们！
It's Staff Arnold!
是 Staff Arnold!
Yeah, come on.
是啊, 快来
Captain?
队长？
Yeti!
雪怪！
They got two of us!
它们抓了我们两个人！
And the ammo detail - they're all gone.
还有那些弹药, 都不见了
What's the plan then?
那计划是什么？
I brought a load of explosives down from Holborn. I'm going to blow it - and them with it.
我从 Holborn 那里带下来一包炸药．我打算引爆它, 炸了它们
Taking a bit of a risk, aren't you, sir?
得冒点风险, 是吧, 头儿
Yeah, I know.
是的, 我知道
Hey, look what's happening!
嘿, 看看什么情况！
What are they doing?
它们在干什么？
Looks like the cobwebs!
看着像是蜘蛛网！
Cobwebs or not, I'm going to blow it sky high. Get back!
不管是蜘蛛网还是什么, 我要把它炸到天上去．后退！
What's that noise?
那是什么声音？
The boxes are pulsating!
那盒子在脉动！
Get back!
回来！
This waiting's getting on my nerves. Why the heck don't they do something?
这么等着让我更紧张了，他们为什么不做点什么？
Steady, lad. We'll know soon enough.
稳住, 小伙子。我们很快就会知道
We can't just stand here. Can't we make a run for it?
我们不能就这么站在这儿，我们要不跑过去吧？
We wouldn't stand a chance, not with them switched on.
我们一点机会都没有, 只要它们的开关还开着
How do you know that?
你怎么知道的？
It's alright, sir. The Professor's vouched for him. Understand he knows a great deal about these robots.
没事的, 头儿。教授为他担保了。你要知道他对这些机器人很了解
See, you have to find out...
看，如果你想搞明白
What's that?
怎么回事？
What made them do that, I wonder?
谁让它们这样的，真奇怪
Couldn't say, sir. But I don't think we should stay to find out.
不好说，头儿。但我觉得我们不要停在这里研究这个
Yes, you're right, Staff. Come on, let's get back.
是，你说得对，Staff。来，我们回去
Wait - can we not just see what they're up to?
等等 -- 我们能不能看看他们在干什么？
No! If there's one thing that I've learned, it's never push your luck. Now come on.
不！如果说有一件事我学乖了, 那就是永远不会用光你的运气。现在赶紧
What is it, sir?
是什么，头儿？
Quiet! Listen.
安静！听
Quick, get in here.
快，到里面去
Soldier!
士兵！
Well, there's a sight for sore eyes!
啊，眼睛都酸了总算看到个人！
Are you stark raving mad?
你疯了吗？
Aye, well I always sing when I'm scared, see.
啊，我害怕的时候就总唱歌, 就这样。
Stand to attention when you're talking to an officer!
和长官说话的时候, 要立正站好！
Name and serial!
名字、番号！
- 6-0...  - Shush!
- 6-0...  - 嘘！
6-0-1 Evans, sir!
601 Evans，长官！
Evans? Anybody know him?
Evans？有谁认识他吗？
Oh, I'm not one of your lot, sir.
哦，我不是你们这伙的，长官
Then what are you doing down here?
那你在这下面做什么？
Trying to get out, Sarge!
在找路出去, 中士!
Don't try to be funny with me, lad! How did you get down here in the first place?
别想跟我开玩笑, 小伙子！你一开始是怎么来这里的？
Driver on the ammo truck to Holborn. Got jumped, we did - quite a dust up, there was.
我是开运弹药卡车的司机．我们被袭击了, 真的 - 一片狼藉
Couldn't get past them hairy creatures, see? Been wandering for hours. Lost, I was.
没法越过那些毛绒怪啊．我在这里转悠几个小时,迷路了
I tried one way, but there seemed to be some sort of cobweb muck moving down the tunnel.
我试过这边, 但似乎有某种蜘蛛网在隧道里移动
Moving? Are you sure it was moving?
在移动？你确定它是在移动？
Well of course I'm sure!... sir. Sounds daft, I know,
我当然确定，长官。听起来有点傻，我知道
but it seemed to be following a Yeti that had a kind of pointed glass thing in its hands.
但它似乎是跟一个雪怪在移动, 雪怪手里有一种玻璃状的尖头器件
Was it shaped like a pyramid?
它是不是是角锥状的？
Well, I suppose it was, really.
嗯，我觉得是，真的
Well that's it! Smash the pyramid, and you put the Intelligence out of action!
那就是了！砸烂那个角锥，你就让大智慧没招了
What Intelligence?
什么智慧？
Whereabouts did you say this happened?
你说这是在哪里发生的？
Kings Cross, Staff.
国王十字车站，Staff
What!
什么！
Headquarters, sir - HQ may be in danger!
总部，头儿 - 总部可能遇到危险了
Yes, we'd better get back as soon as we can. Come on.
是的, 我们最好尽快回去。快来
No, look...
不，你看
Now listen to what the officer said, young man. Come on!
现在听长官的话，年轻人。快点！
Look, I came down here to find the Doctor. I'm not going back till I have!
你看，我是下来找博士的。找到他之前我不会回去！
Now look here...
看看这里...
No, I'm not going! And if I get a chance to smash that pyramid, I will!
不，我不去！而且如果我有机会砸烂那个角锥的话，我会砸的
That's quite a risk you're taking.
你这风险可不小
Aye, but it's me that's taking it.
是, 但反正是我在冒风险
Alright, it's your neck, chum.
好吧，不听就算了
Sir!
长官！
Yes?
什么？
I'd like to volunteer to go with the young gentleman, sir.
我自愿跟这个年轻绅士一起去，长官
Well, you're not one of my lot... alright. Come on, the rest of you.
那个，你也不是我这部分的...好吧。快点，你们其它人
Monument! Then it's Tower Hill next.
纪念版站！那下一站就是塔丘了
Wait a minute! Did you hear something?
等一下，你听到什么了没？
What?
什么？
Listen.
听
Look! The fungus, it's here!
看，真菌，它到这儿了！
We'd better get out, fast!
我们最好出去，快！
- Jamie!  - Doctor! Good to see you!
- Jamie！ - 博士！见到你太好了
All right, Corporal. Nip back and tell Captain Knight it's all clear up 'ere. And get 'em to get a shift on!
好了, 下士．摸回去告诉 Knight 队长这里没问题了．再让他们换个班
Righto, Staff.
好的, Staff
This looks familiar - it's around this corner.
这个地方看起来眼熟 - 应该就在这个角落
Oh no!
噢, 不！
Oh, we can't get to the TARDIS!
噢, 我们没法到 TARDIS 那里了
No, Victoria, I'm afraid we can't.
不能, Victoria, 恐怕不能了
What's happened to Chorley, then?
Chorley 怎么啦？
That's what I'm wondering. Did he reach the TARDIS before the fungus, or... or did he not?
这也是我好奇的地方．他是在大网之前到达了 TARDIS 吗？或者他没有？
You mean to say, he could have got to the TARDIS and already have taken off in it?
你的意思是说, 他可能已经到达了 TARDIS, 并且已经把它开走了？
I don't know...
我不知道
Hey, come back, Doctor!
嘿, 回来, 博士！
It's alright, Jamie, I'm not going to do anything silly. I...
没事的, Jamie, 我不会做任何傻事的
I just want to try and get a little bit for an analysis.
我只是想试着弄一点拿回去分析
Oh Jamie, stop him!
噢, Jamie, 拦住他！
It's alright, Victoria.
没事的, Victoria
Has anyone got a box?
谁有个盒子不？
I've got my tobacco tin.
我有一个香烟盒
Oh, splendid.
噢, 很棒
But then, it's got tobacco in it.
不过呢, 里面还有香烟呢
Never mind.
没关系
Eh!... Oh, alright. I only hope you think the sacrifice is worth it!
诶！...哦, 好吧．我只是期望你觉得我的牺牲是值得的
Hold the tin for me, would you, Evans?
帮我拿着这个铁盒, 行吗, Evans？
Gone and set it off! Come on, now!
走开，放手吧！快点，赶紧！
Oh, it's horrible!
噢, 太可怕了
Go on, Doctor, get it out!
继续, 博士, 把它弄出来
Hold the tin underneath!
拿住下面的铁罐！
There we are - now back, everyone, quickly!
可以了 - 现在退回去，都退，快！
Hello, Staff. It's alright, it's just Staff Arnold!
你好, Staff．没事的，是 Staff Arnold
One of these days, Evans my lad, you're going to creep up onto someone once too often!
总有一天，Evans 你这小子会接连吓死好几个人的(?)
Well, that's life, innit Staff?
嗯, 这就是生活, 对吧 Staff
Any luck at Holborn?
Holborn 有消息吗？
No - fungus.
没有，过不去网
Same back there.
这边也是
Right. I'll tell the Colonel. You lot had better get back to HQ.
好, 我会汇报给上校．你们几个最好回到总部去
We'll be along in a few minutes.
我们过几分钟也会回去
Come on, Jamie, I'll just show this bit of fungus to Travers.
快来, Jamie, 我要把这点真菌展示给 Travers
Right.
好嘞
Hey, look at this!
嘿, 看看这个
Good Lord! That's Yeti!
上帝！那是雪怪干的！
You don't think they may still be here?
你觉得它们已经不在这里了？
I hope not!
我期望不在了！
Oh, Doctor!
噢, 博士！
D'you reckon they have?
你觉得他们已经得手了吗？
Have what?
得手什么？
Taken him? Like she said?
抓走 Travers？正如她所说的？
Yes, I'm very much afraid they have.
是的，恐怕它们真的已经得手了
But why? Why didn't they just kill him? Unless...
不过为什么？它们为什么不直接杀了他？除非...
Yes?
什么？
Well, unless they had a use for him.
除非它们拿他另有用途
Ah, Doctor. What's this I hear about Travers?
啊, 博士, 我听说 Travers 怎么了？
'Scuse me, sir, but I think you ought to come to the Ops Room.
对不起, 先生, 但恐怕你得到操作室来一趟
Why? What's happening?
为什么？怎么了？
That fungus stuff, it's on the move again!
那些真菌网, 又在移动了！
It's like a spider's web, ain't it?
看起来像是蜘蛛网, 是不？
Yes. And we're the flies, alright, but... where is the spider?
是的, 而我们就是苍蝇．好吧, 不过...蜘蛛在哪儿？
Better give the others a hand, Corporal.
最好给其他人帮一下, 下士
Sir.
是！
Doctor. Been thinking about what you were saying earlier,
博士, 我在想你之前说的话
about someone here in HQ being responsible for all this.
你说总部的某个人得为这些情况负责
Could it have been Travers?
有可能是 Travers 吗？
I doubt it.
我表示怀疑
Well, after all he has disappeared.
但是, 不管怎么说他已经消失了
Yes - so has Chorley. I'd say he was a much more likely suspect.
是的, Chorley 也消失了．要我说他更像有嫌疑
True.
的确
On the other hand, of course, whoever is in league with the Intelligence
另一方面来看, 当然，不管谁是大智慧的同盟
could still be amongst us here.
他都有可能还在我们中间
That's a fact of which I am uncomfortably aware.
我也意识到了这个事实, 这一点让我很不安
But tell me, Doctor, this Intelligence - exactly what is it?
不过跟我说说, 博士, 这个大智慧到底是个什么东西
Well I wish I could give you a precise answer.
嗯, 我期望我能够给你一个确切的答案
Perhaps the best way to describe it is a sort of formless, shapeless thing
也许最好的描述是, 它是一种无形无体的东西
floating about in space like a cloud of mist, only... with a mind and will.
像一团云雾一样漂浮在太空中, 只有意识和意志
What's it after? What's it want?
它在追求什么？它想要什么？
I wish I knew. The only thing I know for sure is that it brought me here.
我期望我知道．我唯一确切知道的就是, 它把我带到这里了
Brought you here?
把你带到这里？
Yes, been wondering how you got here.
是．我也好奇你是怎么到这里的
Yes, well I... I don't think there's any harm in telling you now. I...
这个...我觉得现在告诉你们也没有什么问题, 我...
I have a craft, that travels in time and space.
我有一艘飞船, 可以穿越时间和空间
Oh, come now Doctor, you can't expect me to...
噢, 得了博士, 你不会指望我会...
This craft of yours, this time-space craft. Could it get us out of here?
你的这个飞船, 时空飞船, 它能把我们带出这里吗？
Well, yes - but it's at Covent Garden!
嗯, 可以 - 但它现在在科文特花园
What does it look like?
它是什么样子的？
It's a police box.
是个警察亭
Oh really, Colonel, surely you're not...
噢, 真的吗, 上校, 你不会...
So - if we could rescue that craft, you could take us out?
这么说, 如果我们能弄回那个飞船, 你就能把我们带出去？
Yes, yes I could, but I have to stay here and finish Travers' work!
是的, 我可以．但我现在必须呆在这里, 完成 Travers 的工作
Ah, Doctor. Miss Travers is feeling alright now, and would like to see you right away.
啊, 博士, Travers 小姐现在感觉没事了, 现在想马上见你
Very good, Jamie. Excuse me, gentlemen, please.
很好, Jamie．请原谅, 先生们
Yes.
好的
Well, I've heard some stories in my time, but that one really takes...
哈, 我这辈子听过不少故事, 那个故事还真是...
So you don't believe him?
看来你不相信他？
No, of course not, sir! The whole idea is screwy. A police box!
不, 当然不, 头儿！整个故事都很怪诞, 警察亭！
Well whether you think it foolish or not, we are going to rescue that craft.
好了, 不管你觉得它是不是傻, 我们都要去找那艘飞船
Oh, but sir! Our job...
噢, 但是头儿！我们的任务...
Captain Knight. The Army has failed to defeat this menace.
Knight 队长, 在消除这个威胁上面, 军队已经失败了
Now the Doctor thinks he might succeed. Personally, I doubt it.
现在博士觉得他可能成功．个人来说，我也表示怀疑
But if we stay here, we're as good as dead.
但如果我们待在这里, 我们还是死翘翘
Therefore I do not intend leaving any escape route unexplored,
所以不可能还有一条路而我不去尝试
however... screwy you may think it.
不管这条路你觉得如何怪诞
Oh, surely Colonel...
噢, 好吧上校
Let's get on with it, shall we, Knight?
我们开动吧, 行不, Knight？
Sir.
是！
But... but there must be a chance! If the Doctor says...
但是...肯定还有可能的！如果博士说...
No, the soldiers could comb these tunnels for a fortnight and still never find him.
不, 士兵们在隧道里来回排查两周, 也不一定能找到他
I'm afraid your father's been taken by the Intelligence.
我担心你的父亲已经被大智慧给抓走了
The only way that we can save him is by finding the central control source.
我们能救他的唯一途径是找到中心控制源
Aye, if it's anywhere, that's where he'll be.
是, 那东西在什么地方, 他就在什么地方
But why? Why him? Why not me, or one of the soldiers, or...
但是为什么？为什么是他, 而不是我, 也不是其他哪个士兵, 抑或...
Yes, I know. Tell me, what was your father working on
是的, 我知道．告诉我, 你父亲之前在研究什么？
just before the Yeti broke in, Anne?
就在雪怪闯入之前, Anne?
Um... oh, we were ready to test the sphere with the control unit,
嗯...哦, 我们已经准备好要用控制器来测试球体了
but I don't see what this has to do with anything, Doctor.
但我看不出来这跟这些有什么关系, 博士
But don't you? If he was near to success...
看不出吗？如果他快要成功了...
That's why they took him!
那就是它们抓走他的原因
Well, it's a possibility, isn't it?
对，这是有可能的，是不？
Now Anne, do you feel strong enough to come back to the laboratory?
现在，Anne，你觉得你恢复得怎样了，可以回到实验室吗？
Yes, yes of course.
可以，当然可以
Anything we can do?
我们能做点什么？
No, no, you just take it easy, Jamie.
不，不用，你就休息一下吧，Jamie
What's the matter?
怎么了？
I've been thinking about what the Doctor said.
我在想博士所说的是
Anything we do, the Intelligence always knows!
不管我们做什么，大智慧总是知道！
Aye, but I wouldn't let it worry you. The Doctor will soon find a way out.
是，不过我不会让这个事烦你。博士很快会找到解决办法的
I wish I could believe that.
真期望我能相信那个
Oh yes. Yes, this seems to be in order, Anne.
哦是的，是的，这似乎是正常的，Anne
My father didn't want it put together until this was in proper order.
我父亲不想在一切就绪之前不想把组合拼起来
Very wise. Let's have a look at this...
很明智。我们来看看这个
Oh yes, yes... My word, this is a splendid piece of work, Anne.
啊是，是的...我得说，这是一件了不起的作品，Anne
Thank you.
谢谢你
Yes, this should control the sphere, alright.
是的，这可以操纵球体，很好
But would it override the commands issued by the Intelligence, I wonder?
但它能否压制大智慧发出的命令呢，我想知道
No. No, I'm afraid it won't. I just didn't have the time. Do you think we can do it.
不，恐怕不能。我还没有时间来弄。你觉得我们可以搞定吗？
Oh, we can do it, if you've got the right bits and pieces.
哦，我们可以搞。只要你有正确的零配件
Hope I'm not disturbing, Doctor, but Staff asked me to give you this.
期望我没打扰你，博士。不过 Staff 让我把这个交给你
Where'd you get this?
你从哪儿得到这个的？
On the floor, by that young lad Weams, it was.
地上, Weams 那个年轻小伙子捡到的
But this is what brought the Yeti to the explosives store!
但就是这个东西把雪怪引到炸药储藏室的
It's obviously been reprogrammed as a homing device, and you've given it to me!
很显然它被改成了一个发出归巢信号的装置, 而你居然把它给了我！
Here! You don't think I had anything to do with these Yeti, do you?
嘿, 你不是认为我跟这些雪怪有什么关系吧, 是吗？
Doctor! The other models - they've gone!
博士！其它的模型呢, 不见了！
Well don't look at me! I didn't want to come down here in the first place
别看我啊！我一开始就不想下到这里来
I shouldn't be down here at all, really. Driver, I am, see.
我根本就完全不该到这里来, 真的, 我只是个司机, 对不
You'd better have this, before you say I've nicked it.
你最好拿走这个, 免得你又说我藏匿了它
Thank you.
谢谢你
And I'll have the tin back, when you've finished with it.
而且等你用完了, 我还要把铁盒拿回来的
Don't look so unhappy - we're all under suspicion, you know, including me.
别那么不高兴 - 我们所有人都有嫌疑, 你知道的, 包括我
Hmm!
哼！
What's in the tin, Doctor?
铁盒里面有什么, 博士？
It's the fungus from the tunnel. I thought if we examined it, it might give us a clue.
是在隧道里面采集的真菌, 我想如果我们研究一下它的话, 也许会有点线索
I must get this dismantled. It's like holding a time bomb.
我得把这个破解掉, 感觉像拿着一颗定时炸弹似的
So my party will get above ground and approach Covent Garden by Neal Street. Is that clear?
我的人会到地面上去, 从尼尔街往科文特花园站靠拢, 清楚了吗？
Now Staff here will be taking the trolley through the tunnel,
Staff 现在就把推车从这里弄到隧道里面去
and will arrive, we hope, at the same time as we do. You picked your two men, Staff?
期望跟我们同时到达目标．你选两个你的人带上, Staff？
Yes, sir. Lane and Evans.
是, 头儿, 就 Lane 和 Evans 吧
Right. Now as soon as we get there, we shall be looking for a police box.
好．等我们一到那里, 就开始寻找一个警察亭
A police box, sir?
一个警察亭吗, 头儿？
Yes, a police box. Now I want that box either out of the station
是的, 一个警察亭．现在我想要的是尽快将它弄出站去
and onto the trolley as quickly as possible. Is that understood?
然后弄到推车上, 清楚了吗？
Yes, sir.
是, 长官
Right. Any questions?
好, 还有问题吗？
Yes, sir, this, um... police box. Is it important?
有, 长官．这个...警察亭, 它重要吗？
Corporal Blake, we'd hardly be going to this trouble if it weren't.
Blake 下士, 如果它不重要，我们就不用费这个事了
Who's going to look after the civilians, sir?
谁来照看这几个平民, 长官？
I'd like you to stay behind and look after them, Captain Knight.
我期望你留下来照看他们, Knight 队长
The Doctor's got work to do. Right gentlemen, time to go.
博士还有工作要完成．好了先生们, 该行动了
- Ah, Doctor.   - Oh Jamie, what is it?
- 啊，博士   - 哦，Jamie，什么事
The Colonel says to tell you he's on his way.
上校让我告诉你他们已经出发了
On his way where?
出发去哪儿？
To rescue the TARDIS!
去寻回 TARDIS！
He's wasting his time.
他是在浪费时间
Well that's what I told him. And I think that man Chorley must be behind...
我也是这么跟他说的。而且我觉得那个 Chorley 应该在背后...
Now look! Get behind me, both of you, and keep clear. Here we go...
来看！到我后面去，你俩都是，别乱动。开始了
No!
不！
What is it, Doctor?
怎么了，博士？
The tin's empty!... Evans!
铁盒是空的！... Evans！
Course, really I shouldn't be doing this, you know, Staff.
当然，我真不该这么干，知道吗，Staff
Not officially on the strength down here, see.
What I am really is a driver, you see...
但实际上我只是个司机，你看...
Don't try to come the old soldier with me, lad!
别跟我玩老兵油子那一套，小子！
Who, me?
谁，我吗？
Yes, you! And when we get in the tunnels, don't you try to skive off,
是，你！等我们进了隧道，你别想溜走
'cos if you do I'll have you for breakfast. D'you understand?
如果你要溜，我会把你当早餐吃了，明白吗？
Trolley's ready, Staff.
推车准备好了，Staff
Right, come on!
好，快点！
So far, so good. If we don't see any Yeti,
目前一切还好。如果没有碰到雪怪...
we should make Covent Garden in about ten minutes. Come on!
我们应该能在10分钟左右到达科文特花园站。快点
Captain, they've gone
队长，他们已经走了
and Evans with them, I think. I can't find him anywhere.
估计 Evans 也跟他们一起走了。我哪儿也找不到他
Yes, well we'd better question Evans carefully when he gets back.
好，等 Evans 回来我们得仔细盘问他
Aye, if he gets back.
是，如果他还回来
It's a funny business, Doctor, that fungus disappearing.
这真是怪事，博士，真菌居然不见了
Yes, yes I know... Don't worry about that just at the moment.
是的，我知道...这会儿先别操心那个
I've been working on this control box with Miss Travers.
我跟 Travers 小姐在研究这个控制盒
There's a few more things I need - transistors, circuits...
我还需要一些东西，晶体管，电路...
Aren't there any in Stores?
储藏室里面没有吗？
No, not of the right type.
没，没有合适的型号
Well in that case, Doctor, I can't help you.
那这种情况下，博士，我就帮不了你了
Well - I was wondering... if I could go up to street level...
是这样，我在想，能不能上去到街上...
The mist! Or the Yeti!
有雾瘴，还有雪怪！
There's no mist directly above us here - we'd have to risk the Yeti.
在我们的正上方没有雾瘴，雪怪的险我们得冒
No. No, I'm afraid that's out.
不, 不行, 恐怕这不行
It's terribly important. Please!
这事非常重要, 求你了！
It'll only take five minutes.
大约只需要五分钟
Alright. I'll get my gear.
好吧, 我去拿我的工具
Well done, Travers!
干得好, Travers!
The Colonel will be through there at Covent Garden in a few minutes, right?
上校再过几分钟内就会到达科文特花园, 对吧？
Do you think they'll be able to load the police box on here, Staff?
你觉得他们会将警察亭送到这里来吗, Staff?
Well, if we can get this thing through the fungus stuff...
唔 - 就看我们能否把这个东西穿过真菌网了...
...there's not much of a gradient in this section of the tunnel.
...隧道里面这一片就没有多大坡度了
Right, I want one volunteer.
行, 我需要一个志愿者
Volunteer? That's a dirty word, that is. Not me!
志愿者？ 这词真不好听．我可不干！
Lane?
What for, Staff?
做什么, Staff?
Well, if this thing wants some help going through to Covent Garden, I'm going through with it...
这样, 如果这个东西需要点帮助才能穿过去到达科文特花园, 我就得自己来...
Into that stuff?
进那里面去吗？
Have we got those respirators?
我们带防毒面具了吗？
Well yeah, here.
哦, 是的, 这里
I reckon we should be all right in these.
我估计我们戴着这个应该就没事了
Oh all right, Lane lad. I'll go by meself.
哦, 没事, Lane, 我打算自己过去
No, 'ang on a sec, Staff.
不, 等一下, Staff
That trolley's heavy, it'll take two of us to shift it.
推车很重, 需要我们两个人才能推动
Good lad. Come on.
好小伙, 来吧
You're potty, the pair of you!
你们不行的, 你们俩！
Shut up, will you! Do as you're told.
闭嘴, 行吗！按吩咐的做！
Play that rope out as we go
我们走的时候拉住那个绳子
any sign of trouble whip us out sharpish. Right?
一有问题就把我们死命往外拉, 行吗？
Well, it's your neck.
反正, 是你的脖子
OK.
好
Alright then...
好了
Staff? Staff Arnold?...
Look, sir!
看, 头儿！
In Here! Quick!
进来, 快！
Come on, through the gate!
快点, 到门这边来！
I'm going to find a way out. Split up!
我去找一条出路, 分开！
Yetis - three of them, sir!
雪怪 - 它们有三个, 头儿！
Grenades!
手雷！
Right, fire!
好, 开火！
Sir, they're smashing down the gate!
头儿, 他们要把门撞倒了！
We can't hold 'em, sir!
我们挡不住它们了, 头儿！
Over the top, all of you!
到上面去, 都上去！
Grenades!
手雷！
Through the yard, come on!
穿过院子, 快点！
Right, bazooka here to cover the others.
好, 用火箭炮掩护其他人
Dawson! Langley!
Make for the warehouse!... Murphy!
冲到仓库去！...Murphy！
There it is again, Doctor!
又有了，博士
Just one more thing.
还有一件事
For heaven's sake, hurry up!
看在上帝的份上, 赶快！
I just need one more component. I'll look through here.
我就还需要一个零件, 我要去这里找找
Doctor! Doctor, look out!
博士！博士, 小心！
No! No!
不, 不！
And this was in his pocket, you say?
你是说，这在他口袋里？
How did he get it? You said it was stolen.
他是怎么拿到的？你说过它被偷了
You can't think that he...
你不是觉得他...
No no no, he didn't steal it. The person who did planted it on him.
不, 不, 不是他偷的．偷的人放到他身上的
Hmm!
嗯！
Eh, don't you try and pin this on me, boyo!
嗯, 你别试图把这事栽到我头上，少年
Strikes me, anything goes wrong around here and I'm always the one to get the blame.
很受打击啊，这里一有什么事情不对, 我总是背锅的那一个
Alright, alright, let's keep our temper, shall we?
好啦, 好啦, 我们都控制一下脾气, 好吗？
The point is, two of these were missing. Now where's the other one?
问题的关键是, 之前有两个不见了, 现在还有一个在哪儿？
There. That one shouldn't bother us any more.
好了，这个不会再烦扰我们了
Now then, come along, Anne, let's get down to work.
现在, 过来, Anne, 我们聚焦工作
Where did I put those bits and pieces?
我把那些零件放哪儿了？
I wish I knew who put it in the Captain's pocket.
我期望我知道是谁把他放到队长的口袋里了
Well it must have been Chorley.
嗯, 肯定是 Chorley
Well look, he left ages ago.
但你看, 他早就离开了
It doesn't matter. He could still...
这无关紧要, 他仍然可以...
Colonel!
上校！
Are you alright?
你没事吧？
What's happened?
怎么了？
Colonel, what happened?
上校, 发生什么了？
Gone.
没了
Not all of them?
不是所有人吧？
All of them?
所有人？
I said so, didn't I? All of them.
我说过了, 是不？所有人
Evans, what about your party?
Evans, 你那边怎么样？
Arnold?
Gone, sir.
也没了, 头儿
Captain Knight, too.
Knight 队长也是
Knight! Hopeless.
Knight! 没希望了
Can't fight them - it seems...indestructible.
斗不过他们 - 看起来它是...刀枪不入的
Can't fight them! You were right, Doctor.
没法跟它们打！你是对的，博士
when you said they were...formless, shapeless... you were right.
你说过它们是...无形无体的...你说的是对的
Listen... listen, everyone! It's the other Yeti model!
听...听, 所有人！还有一个雪怪模型！
It's here! It's somewhere in this room!
在这里！在这个房间里某个地方！
That noise, I've been hearing it on and off all day...
那个声音, 我一整天都时不时听见...
Your pockets!
你的口袋！
What?
什么？
Open your pockets, Colonel! Quickly, quickly, come on!
打开你的口袋, 上校！快, 快, 快点！
How... how...
怎么...怎么...
They bring the Yeti!
是它们招来雪怪！
Oh no!
噢，不！
I just don't understand what's happening!
我就没明白发生了什么？
Poor Travers!
可怜的 Travers ！
Silence!
安静！
Father!
父亲！
- No, no! No!  - But I must..
- 不，不    - 但我必须
No, Anne! Don't go near him.
不，Anne，别靠近他
I... am... the Intelligence!
我...是...大智慧！
- ANNE: No. No   - He can't be.
- 不, 不    - 不可能是他
Listen to me! I speak to you with this man's voice.
听我说！我通过这个人的声音同你们说话
because the time has come for you to understand my purpose.
因为现在是时候让你们了解我的目的了
What's he getting at?
他是什么意思?
Quiet!
安静！
What do you want?
你想要什么？
You defeated me in Tibet, Doctor.
你在西藏打败了我，博士
Yes.
是的
Now you have fallen into the trap that I have so carefully prepared for you.
现在你落入我的圈套了，如此精心地为你准备的圈套
What do you want?
你想要什么？
You! Your mind will be invaluable to me. Therefore I have invented a machine...
要你！你的大脑对我来说将是无价的。因此我造了一架机器...
...that will drain all past knowledge and experience from your mind.
...可以从你的大脑抽取你过去所有的知识和经验
But you'll kill him!
那会杀死他的！
Oh, no. He will survive, his mind unharmed - only empty
噢，不会。他会活下来，大脑也不会受损，只是空了
You can't - we'll fight!
你不能 - 我们会反抗！
That will not do. The Doctor must submit willingly.
那没有用。博士必须自愿服从
And if I... if I do submit, what of the others?
如果...如果我服从，其他人会怎样？
Then the others will go free.
那其他人可以走
And my father too?
我父亲也可以吗？
Oh, him too. I'm only using his body to communicate with you.
哦，他也会。我只是用他的躯体同你们交流
He didn't help you before, then?
他以前没帮助过你吧？
Oh, no. I have many other human hands at my command.
哦没有。我还有其他不少人听我使唤
And who are they?
他们都是谁？
Always questioning! Even now, you're seeking to destroy me!
这么多问题！即使到现在，你也还在寻求毁灭我的方法！
I see I shall have to guide your thoughts.
我看我必须引导一下你们的思想了
No, Jamie, no!
不, Jamie, 不要！
Cooperate and the child will be unharmed.
合作的话这孩子就没事
You have twenty minutes to make up your mind.
你有二十分钟时间做决定
Let me go, Doctor!
放开我, 博士！
Jamie, don't be a fool! You don't stand a chance.
Jamie, 不要犯傻！你一点机会都没有
Let me go! Victoria!
放开我！Victoria!
Let me past, Colonel!
让我过去, 上校！
No. The Doctor's right. There've been enough lives wasted.
不, 博士是对的．已经有太多性命被浪费了
Please... my wrist... Professor!
求你了...我的手腕...教授！
Eh! Wait a minute!
呃！等一下！
What is it, Evans, what's the matter now?
什么事, Evans, 现在什么情况？
Stand back everyone!
每个人都往后退！
I thought I heard it go!
我觉得我听到它走了！
Yes, well we'd better make sure.
是, 但我们最好要确认清楚
Evans - you, myself and McCrimmon will go and search the place.
Evans, 你, 我和 McCrimmon 去搜一下这个地方
Doctor, you'd better stay behind here and get on with your tinkering.
博士, 你最好待在这里, 继续你的破解工作
Professor, please, you're hurting me! My wrist! Professor!
教授, 求你了, 你弄疼我了！我的手腕！教授！
Yes... yes, that should complete the circuit, good... I wonder...
是的... 是, 这样这个电路就完成了, 很好... 我在想...
There's only one way to find out.
只有一个方法可以弄明白
Yes. Certainly no sound out there.
是的．可以肯定的是外面没有声音
Shall we chance it, then?
我们赌一下, 怎样？
Why not?
为什么不呢？
Now!
开!
No! Back! No!
不, 关上, 不！
Push! Push! Push, hard as you can! Push, get your back to it! Get your back to it!
推, 推, 尽力往前推！用背顶上, 用你的背顶上！
Fire door - by the stairs - go and unhitch it, and I'll try to hold this. Go on, McCrimmon!
防火门, 梯子旁边那个, 你去把它打开．我尽力顶住这个, 快, McCrimmon
You sure?
你确定吗
Yes, go on! Go on!
是的, 继续, 继续！
Alright, Colonel, come on!
好了, 上校, 快点！
Strange, it's not picking up.
很奇怪, 它不接收信号
The Intelligence must be transmitting... I wonder why it's not working...
大智慧一定在传输... 很奇怪它为什么不工作...
Aha! Success! It's going, Anne! Come along.
啊！成功了！它可以走了, Anne！快过来
Oh, oh that's marvellous. I'm sorry I'm being so long - this is such a fiddling job.
哦, 这太棒了．很抱歉用了这么长时间 - 还真有点费神
Help you in a minute...
自己玩一会儿吧
There we are. Now then...
到那里去吧, 现在...
Yes, you see, it's homing!
对了, 你看, 它在归巢！
There we are...
再来看看...
Do we go on or turn back?
我们是继续呢还是掉头？
Let's go on.
我们继续
Right.
好
Come on, what are you waiting for?
快点, 你在等什么呢？
Hey, wait a minute!
嘿, 等一下！
This is Victoria's! We're on the right track!
这是 Victoria 的！我们走对了
No, don't shoot!
不, 别开枪！
Is that thing on our side, then?
那东西是我们这边的, 这么说？
It is now. Stop!
现在是了．停下！
Were you scared?
你害怕了吗？
Eh? Oh no, no, I mean, I just got up here to get a better aim, that's all.
呃？哦不, 不怕．我是说, 我上来只是为了好瞄准, 仅此而已
How did you make it stop then?
你怎么让它停下来呢？
Simple - I told it to.
简单 - 我告诉它停就停
Here - ball. Why don't you go back where you come from?
嘿 - 球, 你为什么不回到你来的地方？
Now, pull the other one.
现在, 拿出那一个
Oh, show him, Doctor.
哦, 给他看看, 博士
Alright, I will. Move forward.
好, 我会的．前进
Stop... Move to the left... Stop.
停... 向左移动... 停
There you are, how about that?
你看看, 感觉怎么样？
Hey, that's great! Make a smashing toy, that would.
嘿, 太棒了！这可变成一个强力玩具了
Toy? That's a highly complex piece of equipment.
玩具？那可是一个高度复杂的设备
Oh, is it? Well I don't see how it's going to help us.
哦, 是吗？但我看不出来它怎么能帮我们
But it obeys our commands!
它会服从我们的命令！
So?
怎样？
Well, once we get it inside a Yeti, we'll have a powerful ally!
这样, 一旦我们把它装到一个雪怪体内, 我们就有了一个有力的同盟！
Inside a Yeti?
装进雪怪体内？
Yes, certainly. Will you help us?
是的, 当然是．你能帮我们一下吗？
You must be joking, Go near one of them things?
开什么玩笑, 走到那帮东西旁边去？
I may be stupid, but I'm not daft...
我可能是笨点, 但我不是傻子...
Oh very well, Anne, I shall have to do it myself.
哦, 好吧, Anne, 我就自己来干
Oh, I'm coming with you, Doctor.
哦, 我跟你一起去, 博士
No no, it's far too dangerous.
不不, 这太危险了
There you are, what'd I tell you?
看吧, 我怎么说的？
Not another word, I'm coming with you.
啥也别说了, 我跟你去
Hold it.
停下
Staff Arnold? It can't be, we'd given you up for lost!
Staff Arnold？不可能啊, 我们都认定你已经消失了！
Easy, easy...
放松, 放松...
That's it.
好了
Sorry about this, sir.
很抱歉, 头儿
What happened?
发生了什么？
I don't know. Can't remember. I were pushing the trolley through the fungus, and...
我不知道, 想不起来了．我当时正把推车推过那道网, 然后...
and I blacked out. I thought I were... falling.
我晕过去了．我觉得我在...往下掉
When I come to, sir, I were in the tunnels...
当我醒来的时候, 头儿, 我在隧道里...
Where's the Doctor, sir? I met the Professor and the girl back there...
博士在哪儿, 头儿？我在那里遇到了教授和那个女孩儿
Victoria! Is she alright?
Victoria! 她没事吧
Yeti - guarding them, but... I promised I'd tell the Doctor, sir.
雪怪在看着他们, 但...我答应过我要告诉博士, 头儿
Right. Come on, back to HQ.
好, 来吧, 先回总部
I'm going for Victoria.
我要去找 Victoria
Really, we'd stand a better chance if we stick together. Go ahead! Come on, Staff.
真的, 我们待在一起的话机会大些．往前走！来吧, Staff
Doctor's twenty minutes' almost up.
博士的二十分钟快到了
Evans, come out from behind that board.
Evans, 从那块板子后面出来
Oh, it's you, sir.
噢, 是你啊, 头儿
Where's the Doctor?
博士在哪儿？
Evans!
B-b-but y-y-y-you...
但是...你你你...
Stop bleating like a Welsh baa-lamb, Evans, and answer the Colonel.
别像头威尔士羊羔一样咩咩咩．Evans, 回答上校的话
Sir?
头儿？
Doctor and Miss Travers, where are they?
博士和 Travers 小姐, 他们在哪儿？
Gone, sir.
走了, 头儿
Gone - where?
走了？哪儿？
Warren Street, I think.
Warren 街, 好像是
Why?
为什么？
After a Yeti, they said.
去找一个雪怪, 他们说过
Have a look at the board, sir.
看一下监控板, 头儿
Warren Street.
Warren 街
Come on!
快点！
No, not you, Staff. Evans, make yourself useful.
不, 你不要来, Staff．Evans 把自己变得有用些
Get a dressing for the Staff Sergeant's head.
把 Staff 中士的头包扎一下
- Yes, sir.  - Thank you, sir.
- 遵命, 长官  - 谢谢你, 头儿
We're trapped!
我们被包围了！
Give me the control box, Anne.
把那个控制盒给我, Anne
- The control box...   - Yes.
- 控制盒...   - 对
Haven't you got it, Doctor?
不是你拿着的吗, 博士？
What! What... hold the sphere!
什么！什么...拿着这个球！
Oh Doctor, you must have it!
哦博士, 肯定在你那里
Yes...
是的...
Doctor!
博士
Don't worry, it'll work!... It's got to work!
别担心, 能起作用的！...必须能起作用！
I know you said it only worked at short range, but for a moment...
我知道你说过它只在很短的距离内有用, 但有那么一会儿...
Well, don't tell me you were worried?
哦, 你是想说你有点担心了？
Would you like to hold this for me? Now then...
你能帮我拿着这个吗？现在..
It's alright, it's quite safe.
没事的, 非常安全
Nearly out... there.
快出来了，好了
Right.
行了
Now then - turn round!
现在 - 转身！
Oh, it works! You've done it!
哦, 有效！你成功了！
We've done it, you mean! Now then, with my reprogrammed sphere and your control box,
是我们成功了！现在, 有了我改造的球体, 和你的控制盒
we should be able to work him over quite a distance. And put your arm down!
我们可以长距离控制他．放下手来！
Now we've got a chance, Anne. Come on!
现在我们有点胜算了, Anne．快来！
Oh, mustn't forget him. Come on, Fred, at the double!
噢，不能忘了他。快来，Fred，迅速！
Staff! Staff!
What is it?
什么事？
What is it, Evans?
什么事, Evans？
Come on, Evans lad, get out of it!
快来，Evans，离开这儿！
What are we going to do now, Staff?
我们现在打算做什么，Staff？
The main door should keep the fungus out of the tunnels for a bit.
这道门应该能把真菌网挡住一阵
We must warn the others that HQ's had it.
我们必须警告其他人总部已经沦陷了
Right.
是
Well, come on, then.
那就快来
Oh, oh no, not me.
噢，不，不要找我
You're not disobeying an order, are you, Evans?
你不服从命令是吗，Evans？
Now look here, Staff. If we go up there, and this stuff breaks out, we'll be trapped!
现在你看，Staff。如果我们上去，而这个东西扩散了，我们就被困住了
Now look, lad, you're scared, that's understandable.
听着小子，你害怕，这是可以理解德
But you've been in the Army long enough to know that orders is orders.
但你在军队待得够久了，该知道命令就是命令
There's four people up there. If we don't warn them, they're for the chop.
上面有四个人，如果我们不警告他们，他们就任凭宰割了
So? Four of them's getting the chop - there's no reason to make it six, is there?
所以啊，他们四个被宰割，没理由要变成六个啊，对不？
I've had enough of your lip for one day. Now come on! Follow me.
今天一天我算是受够你那张破嘴了。现在快点，跟着我
Evans! Come back here!
Evans！回来这边！
Not on your nelly! Cheerio, Staff!
不跟你一起了！祝你好运，Staff！
Right, lad - I'll get you for this!
好，小子，我会找你算账的！
Anne...
Hey!
嘿！
Stop! Come back here! ... Stop!
停下！回来这里！... 停下！
Anne, I've been thinking. Until we know who else is working for the Intelligence...
Anne，我一直在想。在我们确切知道还有谁在为大智慧工作以前...
- Everyone must be suspect.  - Yes?
- 每个人都是有嫌疑的   - 嗯?
Well, the fewer people who know this chap's on our side, the better.
知道这个家伙在我们这边的人，越少越好
Yes... yes, and whoever is the Intelligence is bound to know that you're controlling this Yeti.
是的，不管谁是大智慧，他肯定知道是你在控制这个雪怪
Mmm... I know.
嗯... 我知道
You are to remain here for... Do you think a minute will be enough?
你要在这里停留...你觉得一分钟够不够？
What for?
够干什么？
For us to get clear.
够我们俩闪人
Perhaps.
也许吧
You are to remain here for ninety seconds, and then resume acting on orders from the Intelligence
你要在这里停留90秒，然后继续按照大智慧的命令行动
until you are told otherwise. Is that understood?
直到你得到其它指示，明白了吗
Right. Switch off, for ninety seconds, starting from... now.
好。关闭，等待90秒，从现在...开始！
Come on, Anne.
快来，Anne
It is them! Come on!
是他们，快点
Am I glad to see you! There's fungus at Warren Street.
见到你们真高兴！Warren 街也有真菌了
Yes, I know.
是的，我知道
Oh. What are you doing down here, anyway?
噢，你在这下面干什么？
Well, as a matter of fact...
这个，事实上...
I'll tell you another time. Hello, Colonel.
我回头再告诉你。你好，上校
Glad to see you're both safe. Any luck with your gadgets?
看见你俩都安全真是太好了。你们那小玩意运气怎么样？
No. No, I'm afraid not.
不，恐怕不怎么样
Pity.
真遗憾
Any news of Victoria?
有 Victoria 的消息吗？
Yes, she's at Piccadilly Station.
有，她在 Piccadilly 站
Piccadilly?
Is my father there too?
我父亲也在那里吗？
Aye, he's with her.
是，他俩在一块
Are they alright?
都还好吗？
Yes.
是的
How do you know?
你怎么知道的
Ran across Arnold - he saw them.
碰到了 Arnold，他看见过他们
Arnold?
Arnold! But Evans said - the fungus...
Arnold！但 Evans 说过，那些真菌....
Yes, he went into it, alright, but he came out again somehow.
是的，他走进去了，确实，但不知怎的他又出来了
Says he can't remember what happened.
他说他想不起来发生了什么
Well we haven't got any time to find out.
我们也没时间去搞明白
No, time's nearly up.
没有，时间快到了
Yes, your twenty minutes.
是，你那二十分钟
Well come on, then.
那就，来吧
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么？
We can't do anything until we get back to Headquarters,
在回到总部之前我们什么也做不了
and... then, if we've got time, we'll try and increase the range of the control units. Come on!
如果我们还有时间，我们要尽量增加控制器的有效距离。快点
What is it, Colonel?
什么事，上校？
Something up ahead.
前面有什么东西
We can't go back!
我们回不去了！
What, fungus, you mean?
什么，有真菌网，是这个意思吗？
Yes.
是的
Is that you, Colonel?
是你吗，上校？
It's Arnold. Hang on, Staff!
是 Arnold。坚持住，Staff
Why isn't he in HQ?
他怎么不在总部？
Sir - the fungus. It's swamped HQ.
头儿，那些真菌网，已经侵占了总部
No!
不！
I'm afraid so, sir. The main doors should keep it out of the tunnels for a bit, but...
恐怕如此。大门还能把它挡在隧道外面，但是...
Where's Evans?
Evans 在哪儿？
Scarpered, sir.
跑掉了，头儿
Our time's up! We're all together - they've come to fetch us!
我们的时间到了！我们聚在一起，他们来带我们走了
H... hello! If you... if you're looking for your friend, he went that way...
你...你好！如果你们...你们在找你们的朋友，他去那边了...
Look, you don't want me!... I'm not one of them, see?...
我说，你不会想要我的！... 我不是他们中的一员，明白？
Driver, that's what I am... shouldn't be down here at all, really...
司机，我只是个司机... 真不该下这里来的，真的...
Hey, steady on!
嗨，稳住！
Oh, going for a walk, are we? There's lovely.
噢，要散散步，是吗？好温馨啊
I'm going to make a break for it, sir.
我打算冲出去，头儿
- Think you can?  - Well, it's worth a try.
- 你觉得你能？  - 还是值得一试
On the loose, sir, I might be able to do something.
跑出去的话，也许我还能做点什么
If only you could distract them, sir.
但你要帮忙吸引他们的注意力，头儿
Right, Staff.
好，Staff
I think it wants us to go on, sir.
我觉得它想要我们继续走，头儿
Right. Here we go.
好吧，那就走
Wait!... Can't you see, he's fallen over!
等等！... 你没看到吗，他摔倒了！
Be careful, be careful!
小心点，小心！
Where are we being taken, Professor?
我们要被带到哪儿去，教授？
Oh, to meet the Intelligence, I suppose.
哦，去见大智慧，我估计
A pyramid!
一座金字塔！
Yes - but it's different! We... we've never seen one like this before. It's fascinating!
是的，但有些不一样，我们...之前从没见过这个样子的。很有意思！
This must be the machine that the Intelligence intends using on the Doctor.
这肯定就是大智慧说要用在博士身上的那个机器
Oh, no no. No, I shouldn't if I was you.
噢，不，不。我要是你的话我就不会
Yes, I think perhaps you're right.
是的，我想也许你是对的
Why didn't you tell me all this before?
为什么之前不告诉我这些情况？
Him.
他
You don't think the Colonel...
你不会是说上校他...
Well, you never know, do you?
但是，你也不知道啊，对不对？
Which one is ours?
哪个是我们的？
I don't know.
我不知道
What!
什么！
Well unfortunately I've lost track of him.
很不幸，我没跟住它
Oh, that's a great help!
噢，那可帮大忙了！
Well, never mind, I... I want you to take this microphone
这个，别管了...我要你拿着这个麦克风...
... and keep on calling our Yeti to you.
... 一直呼叫，把我们的雪怪叫到你身边来
How will I know I've got the right one?
我怎么知道过来的是对的？
Well, you'll soon know if you haven't got the right one, won't you!
哦，如果不对的话，你很快就会知道，是吧？
Jamie, I hope you don't suffer from claustrophobia!
Jamie，我期望你没有幽闭恐怖症
Sergeant! Oh, oh thank heavens I found you!
中士, 感谢老天我找到你了！
I've been wondering down here by myself for... for ages!
我一个人在这下面转悠了...好几个世纪了！
Well well well, quite forgotten about you, we had, Mr Chorley!
喔喔喔，我们都快忘记你了，Chorley 先生
Tried to get out over the surface, but... there were Yeti everywhere!
试过逃到地面上去，但是...到处都有雪怪！
And there's this... this fungus, and fog, all around, you see, and... it's hopeless!
而这里有这个...真菌网，雾瘴，到处都是，你看，还有... 让人绝望
Where's the control box?
控制盒在哪儿？
Hm?
嗯？
The control box!
控制盒！
It's in my pocket.
在我口袋里
Well, why don't you use it on these Yeti? And then maybe we can escape!
怎么，你怎么不对这些雪怪使用？那样的话也许我们能逃出去
Oh, no. I must meet the Intelligence face to face.
哦，不。我必须跟大智慧面对面
Doctor?
博士？
What is it?
什么事？
Been thinking - the Yeti haven't noticed McCrimmon's disappearance yet.
我在想，雪怪还没有留意到 McCrimmon 已经不见了
Not that I think he'll be able to achieve anything.
倒不是说我觉得他能搞定什么
Go on...
继续...
Well, I don't really know how to say this, but, um...
这个...我真不知道该怎么说，但是...
...there's Miss Travers and Victoria to think of, and, er...
...有 Travers 小姐和 Victoria 要考虑，还有 ...
You mean, am I going to give myself up?
你是说，我是不是会放弃我自己？
Yes. Of course, the decision must be yours, and yours alone.
是的。当然，决定是你自己做，独自做
But the Intelligence did promise to release Travers and Victoria.
但大智慧的确承诺过会放了 Travers 和 Victoria
You believe that?
你相信吗？
Well, why not?
为什么不？
Hello, we've got company.
哈罗，我们有同伴了
Hello, sir!
你好，长官！
Evans, where the devil have you been?
Evans，见鬼你去哪儿了？
Didn't Staff Arnold tell you, sir?
Staff Arnold 没有告诉你吗，长官？
Yes. Sounded very like desertion to me.
是。听起来很像是当逃兵了
Desertion? Me? Oh, good heavens, no!
逃兵？我？噢，老天，不会！
No, I... I thought I'd try a single-handed and desperate attempt to rescue Professor Travers and the girl!
不，我还想我要单枪匹马，死命去救 Travers 教授和那个女孩儿呢
Isn't Staff Arnold about?
Staff Arnold 在这附近吗？
No.
不在
Good!
好！
Listen!
听！
Now listen, everyone - when the Yeti come for you, don't struggle.
听好，所有人。当雪怪过来的时候，不要挣扎
Whatever you do, don't resist them!
你们做什么都行，但不要反抗！
Don't struggle, he says! He must be joking!
别挣扎，他说！他肯定在开玩笑
The Doctor will have to give in. There's no other choice!
博士只能投降，没有别的选择
Aye, aye, time to get fell in!
好，好，大限到了
Thank you!
谢谢你！
Father! Oh, father, are you alright?
父亲！噢，父亲，你没事吧？
Yes, I'm alright again... Don't, don't worry, Anne.
是的，我又没事了... 别，别担心，Anne
Jamie and the Doctor - where are they?
Jamie 和博士，他们在哪儿？
Anne?
Come towards me... Like that, that's it... Come to...
朝我这边来..就这样，对了... 到...
Right now. Raise your right arm.
好了，举起你的右臂
Raise your right arm!
举起你的右臂！
Oh, what's the use?
噢，这有什么用？
Well, there's nothing to be afraid of, dear. Just - just be calm.
好，没什么可害怕的，亲爱的。只要 - 保持冷静
Doctor!
博士
The Doctor!
Doctor!
博士
What are they going to do?
他们打算干什么？
Now don't worry, Victoria.
不用担心，Victoria
But... I...
但是...我...
Everything's under control. Don't be frightened.
一切都在掌控之中，别害怕
But Doctor, what are they going to do?
但是博士，他们要干什么？
Everything is under control. Tell her, Anne, you understand?
一切都在掌控之中。告诉她，Anne，你明白吗？
Yes... yes, I think so.
是的，我想我明白
Now listen, everyone. Don't do anything foolish! I am perfectly alright.
现在听着，所有人。别做任何傻事！我完全没事
Yes, he is perfectly alright. Thank you, Doctor, for being so cooperative.
是的，他完全没事。谢谢你这么合作，博士
Why don't you show yourself? Who are you?
为什么你不现身呢？你是谁？
Silence! You will know soon enough.
安静！很快你就知道了
Chorley!
- Good grief!   - But that horrible little man...
- 老天！  - 但那个恐怖的小家伙...
-  You, the Intelligence?  - No. No.
- 你？是大智慧？ - 不，不是
No no no, he can't be the Intelligence, he can't! It doesn't make sense!
不不不，他不可能是大智慧，不可能！这说不通！
It isn't me! It isn't me, don't you understand!
不是我，不是我，你们不明白吗？
I'm not the Intelligence! The Intelligence is him!
我不是大智慧！大智慧是他！
It can't be!
不可能！
Oh. Arnold
噢，Arnold
No. Merely Arnold's lifeless body in which I have concealed myself.
不，Arnold 这已经没有生命的身体只是我藏身的地方
But let us to work. There will be time for discussion later.
我们还是办正事吧。后面会有讨论时间的
In fact, all the time in the world.
实际上，我们有世界上所有的时间
Oh... so you weren't going to let us go then, afterwards?
噢... 所以你不打算放我们走，完事以后？
Did you think he would?
你还以为他会？
The last member of the party. Come and join us!
聚会的最后一位成员，来，加入我们吧
Oh, Jamie!
噢，Jamie！
Victoria, are you alright?
Victoria，你没事吧
Your solicitude is touching. Nevertheless, it is wasting time.
你们的相互关怀让人感动。但不管怎样，这是浪费时间
Frightened that something might go wrong?
你是害怕出什么岔子？
Join the Doctor.
去博士那儿吧
Do what he says, Jamie.
按他说的做，Jamie
Take him!
抓住他！
Leave him! Leave him be!
别动他！别动他！
I must ensure your complete cooperation, Doctor.
必须确保你会完全合作
Should you prove at all unhelpful, your young friend's neck will be broken.
一旦证明你不太合作, 你这年轻朋友的脖子就断了
You gave your word that no one would be harmed. I refuse to submit until you release Jamie!
你保证过不会有人受到伤害的。我拒绝服从, 直到你释放 Jamie!
Alright. Release the boy!
好吧，放开那孩子！
But at the first sign of trouble from you...
但是一旦发现你有任何制造麻烦的迹象...
Don't worry. I will do what you say.
别担心，你说什么我做什么
Good. Into the machine, Doctor.
很好，到机器里去，博士
Soon your mind will be absorbed by the Great Intelligence.
很快你的意识都会被大智慧所吸收
You should be very proud, Doctor - your knowledge of the past will help to shape the future of this planet.
你应该会很骄傲，博士，你在过去积累的知识将有助于塑造这个星球的未来
Just get on with it, please.
直接开始吧，请
You seem very anxious suddenly.
你似乎突然变得焦急了
I just want it over and done with.
我就想快点结束它
Submission is essential. You must understand, Doctor...
提交过程是很重要的。你必须明白，博士...
...that without your complete cooperation, this transference would be of no value
...如果你不完全合作，传送就没有价值
Should you offer any opposition, either physical or mental...
如果你做出任何抵抗，无论是身体上的还是精神上的...
I shall be forced to punish you, or rather your friends.
我都会被迫惩罚你, 或者更确切地说, 惩罚你的朋友。
Prepare for a great darkness to cloud your mind.
准备好，会有一团黑暗罩住你的意识
Attack now! Attack the Yeti!
开始攻击！攻击那些雪怪！
Stop it! Stop it!
停下！停下！
Get Arnold!
招呼 Arnold！
No, Jamie, no!
不，Jamie，不要
Come on, get the Doctor out!
快，把博士弄出来！
No, you don't understand, you'll ruin everything! No!
不，你不明白！你会破坏了一切！不！
Professor! Anne! Give us some help!
教授！Anne！帮我们一下！
No! No!... No! Leave me be! You don't understand, I've got to stay here!
不不！... 不！别管我！你们没明白，我必须待在这里！
Well, that's that then, innit?
啊，那就是那个东西，是吧？
You blithering Welsh imbecile! Why can't you do what you're told?
你个爱叨叨的威尔士草包！为什么不能跟你说什么就做什么呢？
Hey, now just a minute, Doctor!
嗨，等一下，博士！
If we hadn't pulled you out of that, you'd have been a heap of dust by now.
如果我们没把你从那里面拉出来，你现在已经是一堆黄土了
You're just as bad. I told you to leave it to me! Now you've gone and ruined everything!
你就好了？我告诉过你别管我！现在你破坏了一切！
Ruined every - How can we! We... we've won, haven't we?
破坏了一...我们怎么能！我们...我们赢了，是吧？
No!
没有！
What do you mean, Doctor?
你什么意思，博士
Oh, why didn't they leave it to me? I had crossed those wires on that helmet thing.
噢，为什么他们就不能别管我呢？我已经反转了那个头盔里面的项圈
The Intelligence wouldn't have drained me, I had... would have drained the Intelligence!
大智慧吸收不了我的意识，我本来...还可以吸收他的！
As it is, all it got was a crossed circuit!
现在好了，就只有一个反转的线圈
You mean, all we've done is... is cut off its contact with Earth,
你是说，我们所干的事情是... 切断了他跟地球的联系
it's - it's still out there in space somewhere, flying around?
他，他还在太空中某个地方，飘着？
Precisely! Look!
正是！看！
Oh!
噢！
Oh, poor fellow!
噢，可怜的家伙！
Do you mean to say that Arnold wasn't the Intelligence?
你的意思是说 Arnold 不是大智慧？
No. He was just a poor soldier that was taken over. He was probably one of the first to disappear.
不，他只是个被附体的可怜士兵。他可能是第一个消失的
You mean it might come back?
你的意思是他还可能回来？
Well, it's still around, isn't it? I've failed.
是，他还在附近，对不？我已经失败了
Nonsense, man!
胡说！
You were marvellous.
你太了不起了
Yes. Great victory.
是，大获全胜
I doubt it.
我表示怀疑
No - you were a hero, and you know it.
不，你是个英雄，你知道的
You don't really think so. Do you?
你其实并不这么想，是吗？
Yes, yes I do.
我是这么想
You've got to face facts, old man. Tomorrow you're going to be a household word, a national figure...
你得面对事实，老头。明天你将成为一个家喻户晓的词, 一个全国性的人物.....
- Oh no, oh no!
- Yeah! I want you on my television programme, and...
- 噢不，噢不！  - 是是！我要你上我的电视节目，还要...
Jamie! Victoria! Come along, it's time we left!
Jamie! Victoria! 快过来，我们该走了
...but the Press Conference, Doctor!
...但是新闻发布会，博士
Goodbye!
再见！
But Doctor, Doctor, you... you can't go yet, there are a lot of things I want to discuss with you!
但是，博士，博士，你...你还不能走。还有好多事情我需要和你讨论！
I'm sorry, Travers, we have to go.
抱歉，Travers，我们必须得走了
Where are you going?
你们要去哪儿？
Covent Garden! Come along. Come along, Jamie.
科文特花园！快过来，快过来，Jamie
Bye!... Bye.
拜拜
Where's he going?
他要去哪儿？
Huh? Oh, er, back to his TARDIS, I suppose.
啥？哦，回他的 TARDIS，我估计
You mean this, uh, this time machine thing, it really exists?
你是说这个...时间机器这种东西，它真的存在？
Y... well I, er... oh, explain it to him, Anne, will you?
这个...噢，你跟他解释一下吧，Anne，行吗？
Colonel, I think we'd better check up top, don't you?
上校，我想我们最好上去检查一下，你觉得呢
Right, Professor. Evans!
行，教授。Evans！
Father - father, I...
父亲，父亲，我...
Now don't you go, Miss Travers, I'd er, I'd like you to explain all about this, this time machine for me.
你现在别走，Travers 小姐，我要...我要你给我讲解一下这个，这个时间机器
Oh dear...!
噢天啊....！
Where do we go? Which is the way to Covent Garden?
我们往哪儿走？哪条路是去科文特花园的？
Oh, don't ask me. I've completely lost my bearings.
别问我，我完全失去了方向
All these tunnels look the same to me.
所有的隧道在我看来都是一样
Come on, let's try this way.
来吧，我们试试这边
Well it doesn't matter, anyway. I mean, there's no danger, is there?
不管哪边都没有关系，我是说，没有危险了，是吗？
Well, not from the Yeti, no, but who knows, they might suddenly start the trains again! Come on!
只是没有雪怪的危险。但是，谁知道呢，他们可能突然开动一条列车过来！快点！
Trains?
列车？
Oh!
噢！